export default {
  id: 'low_1006_3_2a',
  name: '상용한자(3학년-2/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '指', answer: ['가리킬 지', 'ゆび、さ(す)', 'し'] },
    { question: '皮', answer: ['가죽 피', 'かわ', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '歯', answer: ['이 치', 'は', 'し'] },
    { question: '鼻', answer: ['코 비', 'はな', 'び'] },
    { question: '有', answer: ['있을 유', 'あ(る)', 'ゆう、う'] },
    { question: '短', answer: ['짧을 단', 'みじか(い)', 'たん'] },
    { question: '温', answer: ['따뜻할 온', 'あたた(か)、あたた(かい)、あたた(まる)、あたた(める)', 'おん'] },
    { question: '暗', answer: ['어두울 암', 'くら(い)', 'あん'] },
    { question: '去', answer: ['갈 거', 'さ(る)', 'きょ、こ'] },
    { question: '返', answer: ['돌이킬 반', 'かえ(す)、かえ(る)', 'へん'] },
    { question: '助', answer: ['도울 조', 'たす(ける)、たす(かる)、すけ', 'じょ'] },
    { question: '拾', answer: ['주울 습', 'ひろ(う)', 'しゅう、じゅう'] },
    { question: '持', answer: ['가질 지', 'も(つ)', 'じ'] },
    { question: '起', answer: ['일어날 기', 'お(きる)、お(こす)、お(こる)', 'き'] },
    { question: '開', answer: ['열 개', 'ひら(く)、ひら(ける)、あ(く)、あ(ける)', 'かい'] },
    { question: '湖', answer: ['호수 호', 'みずうみ', 'こ'] },
    { question: '岸', answer: ['언덕 안', 'きし', 'がん'] },
    { question: '化', answer: ['될 화', 'ば(ける)、ば(かす)', 'か、け'] },
    { question: '氷', answer: ['얼음 빙', 'こおり、ひ', 'ひょう'] },
    { question: '油', answer: ['기름 유', 'あぶら', 'ゆ'] },
    { question: '波', answer: ['물결 파', 'なみ', 'は'] },
    { question: '庫', answer: ['곳집 고', '곳집', 'こ、く'] },
    { question: '荷', answer: ['멜 하', 'に', 'か'] },
    { question: '箱', answer: ['상자 상', 'はこ', ''] },
    { question: '曲', answer: ['굽을 곡', 'ま(がる)、ま(げる)', 'きょく'] },
    { question: '次', answer: ['버금 차', 'つぎ、つ(ぐ)', 'じ、し'] },
    { question: '運', answer: ['옮길 운', 'はこ(ぶ)', 'うん'] },
    { question: '役', answer: ['부릴 역', '부릴', 'やく、えき'] },
    { question: '苦', answer: ['쓸 고', 'くる(しい)、くる(しむ)、くる(しめる)、にが(い)、にが(る)', 'く'] },
    { question: '美', answer: ['아름다울 미', 'うつく(しい)', 'び'] },
    { question: '想', answer: ['생각 상', '생각', 'そ、そう'] },
    { question: '炭', answer: ['숯 탄', 'すみ', 'たん'] },
    { question: '畑', answer: ['화전 전', 'はたけ、はた', ''] },
    { question: '根', answer: ['뿌리 근', 'ね', 'こん'] },
    { question: '深', answer: ['깊을 심', 'ふか(い)、ふか(まる)、ふか(める)', 'しん'] },
    { question: '植', answer: ['심을 식', 'う(える)、う(わる)', 'しょく'] },
    { question: '陽', answer: ['볕 양', '볕', 'よう'] },
    { question: '葉', answer: ['잎 엽', 'は', 'よう'] },
    { question: '農', answer: ['농사 농', '농사', 'のう'] },
    { question: '緑', answer: ['푸를 록', 'みどり', 'りょく、ろく'] },
    { question: '予', answer: ['미리 예', 'あらかじ(め)', 'よ'] },
    { question: '代', answer: ['대신할 대', 'か(わる)、か(える)、しろ、よ', 'たい、だい'] },
    { question: '申', answer: ['거듭 신', 'もう(す)', 'しん'] },
    { question: '央', answer: ['가운데 앙', '가운데', 'おう'] },
    { question: '注', answer: ['부을 주', 'そそ(ぐ)', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '柱', answer: ['기둥 주', 'はしら', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '決', answer: ['결정할 결', 'き(める)、き(まる)', 'けつ'] },
    { question: '坂', answer: ['언덕 판', 'さか', 'はん'] },
    { question: '皿', answer: ['그릇 명', 'さら', ''] },
    { question: '豆', answer: ['콩 두', 'まめ', 'ず、とう'] },
    { question: '具', answer: ['갖출 구', '갖출', 'ぐ'] },
    { question: '第', answer: ['차례 제', '차례', 'だい'] },
    { question: '洋', answer: ['큰 바다 양', '큰 바다', 'よう'] },
    { question: '服', answer: ['옷 복', '옷', 'ふく'] },
    { question: '階', answer: ['섬돌 계', '섬돌', 'かい'] },
    { question: '童', answer: ['아이 동', 'わらべ', 'どう'] },
    { question: '湯', answer: ['끓일 탕', 'ゆ', 'とう'] },
    { question: '銀', answer: ['은 은', '은', 'ぎん'] },
    { question: '羊', answer: ['양 양', 'ひつじ', 'よう'] },
    { question: '死', answer: ['죽을 사', 'し(ぬ)', 'し'] },
    { question: '世', answer: ['인간 세', 'よ', 'せい、せ'] },
    { question: '界', answer: ['지경 계', '지경', 'かい'] },
    { question: '両', answer: ['두 량', '두', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '由', answer: ['말미암을 유', 'よし', 'ゆ、ゆう、ゆい'] },
    { question: '板', answer: ['널빤지 판', 'いた', 'はん、ばん'] },
    { question: '級', answer: ['등급 급', '등급', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '表', answer: ['겉 표', 'おもて、あらわ(す)、あらわ(れる)', 'ひょう'] },
    { question: '面', answer: ['낯 면', 'おも、おもて、つら', 'めん'] },
    { question: '丁', answer: ['고무래 정', '고무래', 'ちょう、てい'] },
    { question: '区', answer: ['구역 구', '구역', 'く'] },
    { question: '州', answer: ['고을 주', '고을', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '県', answer: ['고을 현', '고을', 'けん'] },
    { question: '都', answer: ['도읍 도', 'みやこ', 'と、つ'] },
    { question: '庭', answer: ['뜰 정', 'にわ', 'てい'] },
    { question: '他', answer: ['다를 타', 'ほか', 'た'] },
    { question: '悲', answer: ['슬플 비', 'かな(しい)、かな(しむ)', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '勉', answer: ['힘쓸 면', '힘쓸', 'べん'] },
    { question: '問', answer: ['물을 문', 'と(う)、と(い)、とん', 'もん'] },
    { question: '章', answer: ['글 장', '글', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '漢', answer: ['한수 한', '한수', 'かん'] },
    { question: '族', answer: ['겨레 족', '겨레', 'ぞく'] },
    { question: '守', answer: ['지킬 수', 'まも(る)、も(り)', 'しゅ、す'] },
    { question: '昔', answer: ['옛 석', 'むかし', 'せき、しゃく'] },
    { question: '祭', answer: ['제사 제', 'まつ(る)、まつ(り)', 'さい'] },
    { question: '和', answer: ['화할 화', 'なご(む)、なご(やか)、やわ(らぐ)、やわ(らげる)', 'わ、お'] },
    { question: '係', answer: ['맬 계', 'かか(る)、かか(り)', 'けい'] },
    { question: '育', answer: ['기를 육', 'そだ(つ)、そだ(てる)、はぐく(む)', 'いく'] },
    { question: '定', answer: ['정할 정', 'さだ(める)、さだ(まる)、さだ(か)', 'てい、じょう'] },
    { question: '昭', answer: ['밝을 소', '밝을', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '秒', answer: ['시간 단위 초', '시간 단위', 'びょう'] },
    { question: '調', answer: ['고를 조', 'しら(べる)、ととの(う)、ととの(える)', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '整', answer: ['가지런할 정', 'ととの(う)、ととの(える)', 'せい'] },
    { question: '様', answer: ['모양 양', 'さま', 'よう'] },
    { question: '度', answer: ['법도 도', 'たび', 'ど、と、たく'] },
    { question: '実', answer: ['열매 실', 'み、みの(る)', 'じつ'] },
    { question: '笛', answer: ['피리 적', 'ふえ', 'てき'] },
    { question: '港', answer: ['항구 항', 'みなと', 'こう'] },
    { question: '横', answer: ['가로 횡', 'よこ', 'おう'] },
    { question: '倍', answer: ['곱 배', '곱', 'ばい'] },
    { question: '帳', answer: ['휘장 장', '휘장', 'ちょう'] }
  ]
}
